Preliminary Guide to the Robin Chandler Lynn Duke Papers, circa 1930-2003
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Accession (2001-0147)
  - Contents of oversize box 17: (Box 17)
    - Certificate from Harry Truman to Angier Biddle Duke for being Ambassador to Argentina, 1949 (Box 17)
    - Photo Album (Box 17)
  - Contents of oversize box 18: (Box 18)
    - Photo Album, Board of Directors (Box 18)
    - Photo Album, The Visit to the Republic of China by Former U.S. Ambassadors, 1984 (Box 18)
  - Contents of oversize box 19: (Box 19)
    - Fabric Bags, (2) (Box 19)
  - Oversize folder:
    - Medalla al Mérito Turisto [Medal of Touristic Merit] from the Spanish Ministry of Information and Tourism, 1968 (Box 19)
    - Signed print Finishing Hole at the Inn, undated, by [Jockliebr] (Box 19)
    - Poster, Albertina Präsentation der Graphik 27, 1996 (Box 19)
- Accession (2001-0155)
  - Contents of box 1: (Box 1)
    - Manual for Unaccompanied Ambassadors, (2 folders) (Box 1)
    - UNA-USA Board of Directors, 1990 June 24 (Box 1)
    - The Ambassadorial Seminar, (2 folders) (Box 1)
    - Bureau of European Affairs - Ambassador's Briefing Book (Box 1)
    - Ambassadorial Briefing Book on Norway, (2 folders) (Box 1)
    - Western Europe/NATO Ambassadors Conference - Briefing Book, 2000 November 16-17 (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous Books (Box 1)
  - Contents of box 2: (Box 2)
    - Videotapes of Duke, (5) (Box 2)
    - Paperweights, (2) (Box 2)
    - Plaque to Angier Biddle Duke, 1986 (Box 2)
    - Presidential Inaugural Information 1977 (Box 2)
    - Drawing of the White House (Box 2)
    - Correspondence, [mainly Christmas cards - one from Al Gore], 1991 (Box 2)
    - Photographs, possibly Christmas, undated (Box 2)
  - Contents of box 3: (Box 3)
    - Trip to Lillehammer, 2000 (Box 3)
    - Photographs of Angier Biddle Duke, a few with President John F. Kennedy and President of India (Box 3)
    - Daily Schedules for Duke in Norway (Box 3)
    - Tourist Information on Norway and Europe (Box 3)
    - Information on Population Control and Women's Reproductive Health, specifically Planned Parenthood, 1994 (Box 3)
    - Personal Correspondence, 1994 Fall (Box 3)
  - Contents of box 4: (Box 4)
    - Daily Schedules of Duke in Norway (Box 4)
    - News clippings and Magazine Articles (Box 4)
    - Correspondence, 2000 and misc. dates (Box 4)
    - Photographs of Duke's family (Box 4)
    - Speeches in Oslo, 2000 (Box 4)
  - Contents of box 5: (Box 5)
    - Daily Schedules for Duke in Norway (Box 5)
    - Correspondence, 2000 (Box 5)
    - Information on Norwegian Embassy (Box 5)
    - Newsclippings and Magazine Articles (Box 5)
  - Contents of box 6: (Box 6)
    - Newspaper Clippings on Population Control and Women's Reproductive Rights, specifically Planned Parenthood (Box 6)
    - Papers by Duke, 1970s-1980s (Box 6)
    - Articles on Duke, 1970s-1980s (Box 6)
    - Information on UNESCO Conference (Box 6)
    - Tourist and Embassy Information on Norway (Box 6)
  - Contents of box 7: (Box 7)
    - Daily Schedules for Duke in Norway (Box 7)
    - UNESCO Conference, 1990s (Box 7)
    - Correspondence, 1980s-1990s (Box 7)
    - News clippings and Magazine Articles on Women's Reproductive Rights (Box 7)
    - Tourist Information on Norway (Box 7)
    - Photographs of Duke, including with Hillary Clinton and Al and Tipper Gore (Box 7)
  - Contents of box 8: (Box 8)
    - Correspondence, 1970s-1980s, 2000 (Box 8)
    - World Childhood Foundation Inc. (Box 8)
    - Notebooks and fliers on various conferences and seminars (Box 8)
    - Photographs of Duke's run for Congress, undated (Box 8)
    - White House Presidential Commission (Box 8)
    - The White House Fellowships (Box 8)
    - Who's Who of Women (Box 8)
    - Congressmen - Population Matters - Letters (Box 8)
    - Congressmen letters to Duke (Box 8)
  - Contents of box 9: (Box 9)
    - Daily Schedules for Duke in Norway (Box 9)
    - Tourist Information on Norway (Box 9)
    - News clippings (Box 9)
    - Correspondence, including autograph of Jimmy Carter and Richard Nixon, 1970s (Box 9)
    - Visit of Lynda Johnson, 1966(?) (Box 9)
    - Photograph of John F. Kennedy (Box 9)
  - Contents of oversize box 10: (Box 10)
    - Photograph of Duke with Lady Bird Johnson with a caption from Johnson (Box 10)
    - Picture of South Elevation, Main Building, Ellis Island, 1990 (Box 10)
    - Metal commemorating Shuttle Orbitor (Box 10)
    - Photo album of Duke visiting women paratroopers in Marrakesh, 1980 (Box 10)
    - Certificate awarding a Degree of Human Letters to Duke (Box 10)
    - Certificate awarding a Degree of Law to Angier Biddle Duke (Box 10)
- (Accession 2002-0162)
  - Contents of Box 1: (Box 1)
    - Albert and Mary Lasker Foundation, 1997-1998 (Box 1)
    - Friends of Art and Preservation in Embassies (F.A.P.E.), 1994-2002, (5 folders)
      - Correspondence and Printed Material, 1994 (Box 1)
      - Correspondence and Printed Material, 1997, (2 folders) (Box 1)
      - Correspondence and Printed Material, 1998 (Box 1)
      - Correspondence and Printed Material, 2001-2002 (Box 1)
    - United Nations Association of the United States of America, 2000-2001 (Box 1)
    - Correspondence (Carbon copies), (4 folders)
      - 1999 June 1-1999 Oct. 25 (Box 1)
      - 1999 Jan. 24-1999 May 6 (Box 1)
      - 1998 Sept. 14-1998 Dec. 31 (Box 1)
      - 1997-1998 (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous Material from various organizations (Box 1)
  - Contents of Box 2: (Box 2)
    - Friends of Art and Preservation in Embassies (F.A.P.E.), 1999
      - Correspondence and Printed Material, 1999, (4 folders) (Box 2)
    - Correspondence
      - 1985-1987 (Box 2)
      - Kerry Committee, 1999 (Box 2)
    - Misc. Material from various organizations (Box 2)
  - Contents of Box 3: (Box 3)
    - Plaque: East River [Savings Bank] Returns to Profitability in 1985 (Box 3)
    - Material related to Senator John Kerry, 1996 Feb. (Box 3)
    - Correspondence
      - 1998 (Box 3)
      - 1998-2001 (Box 3)
      - 2001-2002 (Box 3)
    - Friends of Art and Preservation in Embassies (F.A.P.E.), 1999, (4 folders)
      - Correspondence and Printed Material, 1999, (3 folders) (Box 3)
      - Correspondence and Printed Material, 1999-2000 (Box 3)
    - Misc. Material, including materials for the US-Japan Foundation, 2002 (Box 3)
  - Contents of Box 4: (Box 4)
    - Non-Profit Boards, 1991 (Box 4)
    - Friends of Art and Preservation in Embassies (F.A.P.E.), 1990 (Box 4)
    - NARAL [National Abortion Rights Action League] Foundation, 1991 (Box 4)
    - International Rescue Committee, 2000-2001 (Box 4)
    - Correspondence, 2000-2001 (Box 4)
    - Robin Duke Norway Dept. Papers 2000 (Box 4)
    - Correspondence, copies of clippings, and material on various organizations, 1991-2000 (Box 4)
  - Contents of Box 5: (Box 5)
    - International Rescue Committee (Box 5)
    - Friends of Art and Preservation in Embassies (F.A.P.E.), 1990, 1999 (Box 5)
    - Invitations, 2000 (Box 5)
    - Correspondence and orientation materials regarding Duke's ambasadorship to Norway, 2000 (Box 5)
      Includes a letter from and signed by President Bill Clinton.
    - The Allan Guttamacher Institute, 2002 (Box 5)
    - United Nations Association of the United States of America, 2002 (Box 5)
    - Material related to Duke's ambassadorship to Norway, 2001-2002 (Box 5)
  - Contents of Box 6: (Box 6)
    - Printed material, abortion and pro-choice, 1988, 2001 (Box 6)
    - Material from various organizations, 1999-2001 (Box 6)
    - The Allan Guttamacher Institute, 2001 (Box 6)
    - International Rescue Committee, 2001 (Box 6)
    - Population Action International, 2001 (Box 6)
    - Printed material: Town and Country, 1996 (Box 6)
  - Contents of Box 7 (Box 7)
    - Friends of Art and Preservation in Embassies (F.A.P.E.), 2001 (Box 7)
    - United States-Japan Foundation, 2001 (Box 7)
    - Material Related to Duke's role as abassador to Norway, 2000 (Box 7)
    - Printed Material: Sculpture (Box 7)
- Accession (2003-0096)
  - Contents of Box 1: (Box 1)
    - Dinner Parties, 1988-2001 (Box 1)
    - Dr. William Diefenback (Box 1)
    - U.N. Population Award, 1994 (Box 1)
    - R.C.L. Personal (Box 1)
    - Friends of Art and Preservation in Embassies (F.A.P.E.), Feb. 2000 (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous loose material (Box 1)
      Includes correspondence and documents related to various organizations including the Jefferson Awards, the Council of American Ambassadors, the Feminist Majority Foundation, and Population Action International.
  - Contents of Box 2: (Box 2)
    - Parties, 1985-2001 (Box 2)
    - McKinney Dinner, March 26, 2001 (Box 2)
    - Untitled binder containing correspondence, 1985-1986 (Box 2)
    - Important Documents for Ambassador after Departure from Post (Box 2)
    - Ambassador Duke's Personal Papers (Box 2)
    - Friends of Art and Preservation in Embassies (F.A.P.E.), June 2, 2000 (Box 2)
    - Miscellaneous loose material (Box 2)
      Includes materials related to the Afghan Women's Summit, the Harvard School of Public Health, and the U.N. Association, among other organizations.
    - Committee on the Board, June 29, 2000 (Box 2)
  - Contents of Box 3: (Box 3)
    - Oslo (Box 3)
      Includes correspondence, clippings, negatives, and other documents related to Duke's position as Ambassador to Norway, 2000-2001.
    - Miscellaneous loose material (Box 3)
      Includes material related to the U.N. Foundation, the International Rescue Committee, the U.S.-Japan Foundation, P.A.I., the U.N. Association, and Model U.N., among others.
    - U.N. Association Meeting, March 31, 2003 (Box 3)
  - Contents of Box 4: (Box 4)
    - U.N. Association Meeting, Dec. 16, 2002 (Box 4)
    - Mary Woodard Lasker Public Service Award 2003 (Box 4)
    - U.S. Committee for U.N. Population Fund, May 23, 2002 (Box 4)
    - Miscellaneous loose material (Box 4)
      Includes material related to the International Rescue Committee, the American-Scandinavian Foundation, and the U.N. Association, among others.
  - Contents of Box 5: (Box 5)
    - Institute for Democracy Studies (Box 5)
    - Schedules/Itineraries, February 2001 (Box 5)
      Includes documents related to Duke's position as Ambassador to Norway, 2000-2001.
    - Friends of Art and Preservation in Embassies (F.A.P.E.), 1999-2000 (Box 5)
    - Packard, June 29, 2000 (Box 5)
    - U.N.F.P.A., Jun 1999 (Box 5)
    - Miscellaneous loose material (Box 5)
      Includes material related to organizations including Model U.N., the Lasker Foundation, and the A.S.F., among others.
  - Contents of Box 6: (Box 6)
    - Personal, Jan. 2001 (Box 6)
    - F.A.P.E., Philadelphia, Los Angeles, May-April 2001 (Box 6)
    - P.A.I., 1996-1998 (Box 6)
    - Miscellaneous loose material (Box 6)
      Includes material related to NARAL and the Lasker Foundation, among other organizations.
- Accession (2003-0268), 1998-2003, (3 Boxes)
  Addition (2003-0268) (500 items, 1.4 lin. ft.; dated 1998-2003) contains business correspondence and other materials related to Duke's activism in NARAL, UNESCO, and Population Action International. Also includes a small amount of personal correspondence and 2 VHS tapes, Packing the Courts: The Battle over President Bush's Judicial Appointments and Access Denied: US Family Planning Restrictions in Zambia.
- Accession (2005-0060), 2002-2005, 9 Boxes
  Addition (2005-0060) (3390 items, 5.4 lin. ft.; dated 2002-2005) comprises correspondence, printed material, and board meeting packets related to Duke's activism. Also includes a transcript of oral history interviews conducted by Smith College, and 3 VHS videocassettes.
- Accession (2005-0120), 1992-2005, 3 Boxes
  Addition (2005-0120) (697 itmes, 1.8 lin. ft.; dated 1992-2005) comprises personal and professional correspondence; board meeting packets related to Duke's activism in a wide variety of organizations.
- Accession (2006-0054), 1969-2006, 2 Boxes, 1 Oversize Folder
  Addition (2006-0054) (576 items; 1.3 lin. ft.; dated 1969-2006 and undated) contains correspondence (1993-2006); and other materials related to Duke's activism. There are also 2 CD-ROMs, printed material, clippings, and invitations to luncheons and dinner parties.
- Accession (2006-0062), 1962-2006, 3 Boxes
  Addition (2006-0062) (1025 items; 1.6 lin. ft.; dated 1962-2006 and undated) comprises correspondence, invitations, speeches, printed material, and ephemera related to Duke's activism in organizations (1983-2006). There are also materials that once formed a photo album/scrapbook, with 27 black-and-white photos of the Dukes as well as interior and exterior photos documenting their remodeling of Blair House, the presidential guest quarters, in Washington, DC (undated, probably 1962); invitations; and correspondence (1962-1968), including letters from Jackie Kennedy, Lady Bird Johnson, and others.
- Accession (2006-0092), 1962-2006, 3 Boxes
  Addition (2006-0092) (1025 items; 1.6 lin. ft.; dated 1962-2006 and undated) contains clippings, periodicals and reference works, as well as meeting guides, conference materials, correspondence and other materials regarding Duke's political, charitable and ambassadorial activities. There is also one DVD and two black-and-white copies of family photos.
- Accession (2007-0014), 1962-2006, 4 Boxes
  Addition (2007-0014) (1500 items; 2.4 lin. ft.; dated 1962-2006) contains correspondence, including letters from Jackie Kennedy and Lady Bird Johnson; menus and programs for United States Presidential luncheons and dinners; documentation, pamphlets, and files from councils and organizations; a diploma for Angier Biddle Duke from Duke University; speeches; printed materials; and newspaper clippings.
  - Correspondence, 1988-1996 (Box 1)
  - U.S.-Japan Foundation files, 2000 (Box 1)
  - NARAL and other pro-choice pamphlets (Box 1)
  - Printed materials (Box 2)
    - Vilda säger NEJ (Box 2)
    - Var Drottning klädd för Nobelfest (Box 2)
    - Blair-Lee House: Guest House of the President (Box 2)
  - Files and documentation from several organizations, including:
    - UN Association of the USA (Box 2)
    - John Brandemas Center (Box 2)
    - World Childhood Foundation USA (Box 2)
    - Global Justice Center (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, 2006 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, 2002-2005 (Box 3)
  - Documentation from several organizations (Box 3)
  - Duke University Doctor of Laws degree for Angier Biddle Duke (Box 3)
  - Printed materials:
    - Friends of Art and Preservation in Embassies Tenth Anniversary (Box 3)
    - The Ambassador's Review, Fall 2000 (Box 3)
    - United States-Japan Foundation Twentieth Anniversary (Box 3)
    - The VASA Toolkit (Box 3)
  - Babymother (DVD) (Box 3)
  - Menus and programs from White House luncheons and dinners, 1962-1964 (Box 4)
  - Correspondence, 1963-1966 (Box 4)
    Includes several letters from Jackie Kennedy and Lady Bird Johnson.
  - A Spanish Medal (Box 4)
- Accession (2007-0087), 1964-2007, 3 Boxes
  Addition (2007-0087) (675 items; 0.9 lin. ft.; dated 1964-2007) contains correspondence, photographs, speech transcripts, and conference materials from Duke's charitable and political organizations.
  - Hillary Clinton for President (Box 1)
  - The Official Visit to Greece of Miss Lynda Bird Johnson for the Royal Wedding photograph album, 1964 Sept. 14-19 (Box 1)
  - Speech transcripts, 1974-1980s (Box 1)
  - Population Action Internation, 2007 (Box 1)
  - UN Association of the USA (Box 1)
  - Women's Committee for Refugee Women and Children (Box 1)
  - American-Scandinavian Foundation (Box 1)
  - Interpeace Governor's Meeting, 2007 (Box 1)
  - International Rescue Committee, 2007 (Box 1)
  - Ambassador's Review, Spring 2007 (Box 1)
  - Council on Foreign Relations (Box 1)
  - International Rescue Committee meeting, 2007 April 17-18 (Box 1)
  - Guttmacher Policy Review, Winter 2007 (Box 1)
  - Open Society: SOROS Foundations Network, 2006-2007 (Box 1)
  - Research America, 2006 (Box 1)
  - UN Chronicle, 2006 Sept.-Nov. (Box 1)
  - Faxes (Box 1)
  - Correspondence (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 2)
- Accession (2007-0194), 2000-2007, Interfiled with Accession (2007-0087).
  Addition (2007-0194) (675 items; 0.9 lin. ft; dated 2000-2007) contains correspondence, charitable committee and meeting materials, and a New York Look Book featuring Duke and her fashion sense. This collection has been interfiled with Addition (2007-0087).
  - Accession (2007-0194) (Box 2, continued)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 2, continued)
    - U.S.-Japan Foundation, 2007 (Box 2, continued)
    - Council on Foreign Relations, Annual Report 2007 (Box 2, continued)
    - UN Association of the USA, 2007 Sept. 24 (Box 2, continued)
  - Accession (2007-0194), continued (Box 3)
    - New York Look Book (Box 3)
    - Americans for UNFPA, 2007, (4 folders) (Box 3)
    - American-Scandinavian Foundation, 2007 (Box 3)
    - International Rescue Committee, 2007 (Box 3)
    - International Rescue Committee Freedom Fund (Box 3)
    - UN Chronicle, 2007 June (Box 3)
    - Lasker Awards, 2007 (Box 3)
    - UN Association for the USA (Box 3)
    - World Childhood Foundation (Box 3)
    - Guttmacher Policy Review, 2007 (Box 3)
    - International Flavors and Fragrances shareholders meeting, 2000 (Box 3)
    - Women's Committee of the Central Park Conservancy (Box 3)
    - International Family Planning Perspectives, 2007 (Box 3)
- Accession (2008-0116), 2007-2008, 2 Boxes
  Addition (2008-0116) (600 items; 0.8 lin. ft; dated 2007-2008) includes conference ephemera and other materials from Duke's involvement in charities and political activities; miscellaneous materials and correspondence; and publications from various international organizations.
  - The Ambassador's Review, Spring 2008 (Box 1)
  - Americans for UNFPA (Box 1)
  - Population Action International, 2008 (Box 1)
  - White House Ghosts: Presidents and their Speechwriters, 2008 (Box 1)
  - U.S.-Japan Foundation, 2008 (Box 1)
  - Institute of International Education, 2008 May 7 (Box 1)
  - Riverhouse Realty Inc. (Box 1)
  - UN Association of the USA tribute luncheon, 2008 May (Box 1)
  - Council of American Ambassadors membership directory, 2008 (Box 1)
  - Global Challenge, 2008 (Box 1)
  - Harvard Public Health Review, Fall 2007 (Box 1)
  - American-Scandinavian Foundation (Box 1)
  - Guttmacher Institute, 2008 (Box 1)
  - International Rescue Committee, 2008 (Box 1)
  - U.S.-Japan Leadership Program, 2007 (Box 1)
  - Population Action International, 2007 Nov. 14 (Box 1)
  - From Harm to Home: The Story of the International Rescue Committee, 2007 (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence (Box 2)
- Accession (2009-0168), 1960s-2009, (2 boxes)
  Addition (2009-0168) (900 items; 1.2 lin. ft.; dated 1960s-2009) includes correspondence, board meeting publications from Duke's various charities and organizations, letters from prominent people, and miscellaneous materials such as newspaper clippings and photographs.
  - Correspondence, speeches, 1960s-2000s (Box 1)
    Subjects include population control, abortion, her ambassadorship to Norway, and the New York Cancer Society, among others.
  - Paktiawal, Akhtar Mohammed (Box 1)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1980-2003 (Box 1)
  - Chief of Mission Authorities on Intelligence and Law Enforcement, 1999 (Box 1)
  - VIP letters to Robin Duke (Box 1)
  - Oslo Embassy guestbook, 2000 (Box 1)
  - Photographs of NARAL dinner, 1988 (Box 1)
  - Guttmacher Institute, March 2009 (Box 1)
  - American-Scandinavian Foundation, 2009 (Box 1)
  - UNFPA, 2008 (Box 2)
  - United Nations, 2000s (Box 2)
  - US-Japan Foundation, 2008 (Box 2)
  - International Rescue Commitee, 2007-2009 (Box 2)
  - NARAL (Box 2)
  - Africa Progress Panel (Box 2)
  - New Yorker Look Book (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous folder, no label (Box 2)
    Includes Angier Duke's autopsy (1995), letters and correspondence, speeches, and some news clippings or article reprints.